泰安市二零二三年初中学业水平考试。一。听句子，选择适当的应答语。每个句子读两遍。
1. Could you please help your sister with her English?
2. Hi, Lisa!
I won a prize in the dancing competition yesterday.
3. What do you think of the story U moves a
4. Don't make any noise in the library.
5. Let's go to play basketball after school.
二。听五段对话，选择正确答案。每段对话读两遍。你将有二十秒钟的时间阅读下面五个小题。
6. Mom, the sun is shining.
Can I go to the park with my friend this afternoon?
8. The weather report said it would rain heavily this afternoon.
7. Hello, Miss Green.
I'm not good at spoken English.
What should I do?
9. Don't worry, Bill.
Why not join an English club to practice speaking?
Hello, Miss Green.
I'm not good at spoken English.
What should I do?
Don't worry, Bill.
Why not join an English club to practice speaking?
Good idea. I'll have you try.
8. I never feel time passing when I'm working on math problems.
I like the subject best.
I don't agree with you, Eric.
I think Chinese is more interesting.
9. We are early, Jim.
10. The museum isn't open.
10. Good morning, Ted.
I haven't seen you these days.
Where have you been?
I've been to Sydney to visit my uncle.
Good morning, Ted.
I haven't seen you these days.
Where have you been?
I've been to Sydney to visit my uncle.
听。两段长对话，选择正确答案。每段对话读两遍。听每段对话前，你将有十秒钟的时间阅读对应的三个小题。听第一段对话，回答第十一至十三小题。
Hello, Jeff. Have you finished your homework yet?
Almost. I'll finish it in two hours before lunch.
And after that, I will help my family clean the house in the afternoon.
We have painted it with new colors.
Wow. cool. We've painted the kitchen green.
I prefer green, too.
What about the living room?
The brown walls before looked really bad,
so we've painted them light yellow.
The house looks very modern now.
I can't wait to go and have a look.
Hello, Jeff. Have you finished your homework yet?
Almost. I'll finish it in two hours before lunch.
And after that, I will help my family clean the house in the afternoon.
We have painted it with new colors.
Wow. Sounds cool.
We've painted the kitchen green.
I prefer green, too.
What about the living room?
The brown walls before looked really bad, so we've painted them light yellow.
The house looks very modern now.
I can't wait to go and have a look.
听第二段对话，回答第十四至十六小题。
How are you getting on with your studies, Helen?
Pretty well. I'm busy preparing for the examinations.
I hope to get into a good senior high school.
Do you think you can pass the exam?
Yes, I think so.
I'm very glad to hear that.
What do you want to be in the future?
I want to be a village teacher.
How are you going to do that?
First, I'm going to study in a teacher's college and then work in a village school.
Why do you choose to work in a village school?
I hear many village schools need teachers very much.
So I want to go there to be a
Great. Wish you success.
Thanks a lot.
How are you getting on with your studies, Helen?
Pretty well. I'm busy preparing for the examinations.
I hope to get into a good senior high school.
Do you think you can pass the exam?
Yes, I think so.
I'm very glad to hear that.
What do you want to be in the future?
I want to be a village teacher.
How are you going to do that?
First, I'm going to study in a teacher's college and then work in a village school.
Why do you choose to work in a village school?
I hear many village schools need teachers very much.
So I want to go there to be a Great.
Wish you success.
Thanks Good morning, everyone.
四听短文。回。答下面四个问题，选择正确答案。短文读两遍。你将有二十秒钟的时间阅读下面四个小题。
Now I'd like to introduce some of our school activities next month.
In November, we are going to have the English Festival.
Next Friday, on the 5th, we are going to watch a famous English cartoon, Journey to
the West. After that, reading day is on the 11th.
Then from the 15th to the 17th, we have an English singing competition.
You will enjoy many beautiful English songs.
Then on the afternoon of the 23rd, an English writing competition will be on show.
On the same day, we'll watch a short play called My Dream.
All the actors are from the school acting club.
And then on the last day of this month, you can enjoy a funny film.
Hope all of you can learn something useful through these colorful activities.
Good morning, everyone.
Now I'd like to introduce some of our school activities next month.
In November, we are going to have the English Festival.
Next Friday, on the 5th, we are going to watch a famous English cartoon, Journey to
the West. After that, reading day is on the 11th.
Then from the 15th to the 17th, we have an English singing competition.
You will enjoy many beautiful English songs.
Then on the afternoon of the 23rd, an English writing competition will be on show.
On the same day, we'll watch a short play called My Dream.
All the actors are from the school acting club.
And then on the last day of this month, you can enjoy a funny film.
Hope all of you can learn something useful through these colorful activities.
五。听短文，填表格。根据短文内容写出下面表格中所需信息，每空一词。短文读三遍。你将有二十秒钟的时间阅读表格内容。
Now like school activities 17th, West.
Welcome to our health program.
I'm Dr. Smith.
Today we're going to talk about how to protect our eyes.
Nowadays, many of us get eye problems.
That's because we don't use our eyes in correct ways.
Here's some advice.
We can't watch the screen of a TV, a computer or a smartphone for a long time.
Every 20 minutes, we should stop to look at something far away.
And we are supposed to wear sunglasses when out in the sun.
We'd better not read in the sun.
It's harmful to our eyes.
According to reports, about 35.6 of primary school students and nearly 81
of senior high school students are nearsighted.
So after class, students should be encouraged to go outside during breaks.
Another important thing is to get an eye examination every two years.
If the doctors notice our problems earlier, it'll be easier to correct the problems.
That's all. Thanks for listening.
Welcome to our health program.
I'm Dr. Smith.
Today we're going to talk about how to protect our eyes.
Nowadays, many of us get eye problems.
That's because we don't use our eyes in correct ways.
Here's some advice.
We can't watch the screen of a TV, a computer or a smartphone for a long time.
Every 20 minutes, we should stop to look at something far away.
And we are supposed to wear sunglasses when out in the sun.
We'd better not read in the sun.
It's harmful to our eyes.
We're going to our it'll be easier to correct the problems.
That's all. Thanks for listening.